Software Engineer, Machine Learning, Data Science

Qualifications and research interests_

Systems and Computer Engineer who enjoy doing data analysis and data visualization using R, javascript, python and even C/C++, also web scraping using R, python and bash/shell. Industry experience in data science, machine learning, development and implementation of computational tools for data analysis, data governance and psychometrics. I am interested in the application of machine learning/deep learning and parallel computing tools and techniques in the context of information retrieval.

Technical Skills_

• C++: Simulation, parallel computing, optimization techniques.	8 years
• R/R Studio: Data analysis, machine learning, data mining, web scraping.	6 years
Bash: Tasks automation, web scraping.	6 years
• Python: Tasks automation, web scraping.	5 years
• Java: Web development.	4 years
• C#: Web/mobile development.	3 years
HTML/CSS/JS: front end development, data visualization.	6 years
• Firebase: Data integration, web apps.	3 years
• AWS: Cloud computing architectures and high performance computing environments.	1 years
• BD: MySQL, MongoDB.	4 years
• OS: Windows (6 years), Linux (9 years), OS X (4 years).	9 years

Education

Universidad Nacional de Colombia Systems and Computer Engineering Program

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Computational Neuroscience "Understanding and Modeling the Brain" Seminar

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Urban logistics: agents, objectives and supporting methods for decisions of public/private agents **Seminar**

or built logistics. agents, objectives and supporting methods for decisions of public/private agents between

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Software evolution and maintenance **Seminar**

Experience

Frosthale Group

Lead, specialized software development

December 2019 - Current

2017

2016

2016

2015

- Lead the planning, development, testing and execution of software applications using REST APIs and Websockets of NYSE stockbrokers for the organization optimization of Market Data.
- Implementation of an autonomous application that replaced the platform of purchase orders for complex financial instruments to facilitate and optimize the transactional operation of the Corporate Holding.
- Reverse engineering and data analysis in order to transform data for storage, high availability and consume.

Data Knowledge Consultants

Lead, Data Governance Analyst, Technology Team

July 2019 - December 2019

- Lead of the Data Governance Technology team at Datacrédito Experian
- Development and implementation of workflows for the initiative, focusin on automation.

- Development and implementation of automation solutions for reports.
- Automate policies, standards, and processes
- Design for data quality and model for information relevance

Mundopato

Full Stack developer

April 2018 - December 2018

- Development, testing and maintenance of Web applications.. Tests and analysis to ensure desire functionality.
- Setup and deployment for applications written in R for test scoring, result analysis and classification.

Workapps SAS

Web and Mobile developer using Xamarin(iOS, Android)

July 2016 - July 2017

- Development, testing and maintenance of Web, iOS and Android applications. Tests and analysis to ensure desire functionality and optimization.
- Setup of deployment for applications in multiple platforms (iOS, Android and Web), and ensure compatibility between versions.

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

SICS research group. Developer and Researcher

November 2014 - March 2016

- Analysis, design, implementation and maintenance of numerical application exposed as R packages.
- Workflow management based on git, to coordinate code repositories in which statisticians and developers contribute. Integration of different modules in the package, using interfaces between R and C ++.
- Configuration and deployment of the package for multiple operating systems (Linux, OSX and Windows). Code testing and continuous integration into the workflow.

Personal projects_

sp-feedforward-neuralnetworks

June 2016 - September 2017

A feedforward neural network visualizer and tester using Vue.js, d3, mathjs and firebase.

SPANN / RSPANN 2015 - 2018

C++ artificial neural network library and R package using Rcpp. The library has some models of artificial neural networks and functionalities to experiment.

SPGO / RSPGO 2014 - 2018

C++ optimization library and R package. The library has estructures and algorithms of many optimization methods.

RNeuroEvolution 2017 - 2018

R package that contains some neuroevolution strategies and data visualization tools.

RTimeSeriesPE 2015 - 2016

R package for parameter estimation in the ARMA - ARIMA models using evolutionary computing techniques.

Viviendo-Nuestro-Rock December 2017

Web app developed for the hackathon "BibloRock: una historia 3.0 de Rock al parque" (December 13 and 14 2017).

Volunteer experience

Fe y Alegría Colombia - Fundación Mamá Sara

Volunteer teacher, Estrategia de Validación Comunitaria Hekima

2018

References _____

References will be provided upon request.